because when one thing is developed may
macho there is the penetration of the
various elements there is the
penetration of different elements there
is the analysis of the various elements
which one think mindfulness of the body
because when this one thing is developed
made much of there is a penetration of
the various elements there is a
penetration of different elements there
is analysis of various elements so we
are continuing the Mad Money kiya
audio notes and this is still an go to
Nagoya five seven seven five seven nine
good five eighty five eighty three says
one thing because developed me much of
leads to the realization of the fruit of
stream entry and it is important to note
that at least the realization of the
fruit not to the realization of the
actual insight of the stream entry so
this is another so that it supports
pretty much what satipatthana and
anapanasati suitors already imply and
that is that proper mindfulness can only
be done by somebody who's attained to
the right view and and if they if they
developed by the mindfulness of body or
mindfulness of breathing they will start
to realize the fruit of the stream entry
the fruit of one's returning and so on
and the reason I say it's important to
realize is because often people think
that simply by doing a meditation
technique you you attain the
understanding of freedom from suffering
and so on which is not the case and in
number number of sutras would be will be
mentioning that actually maybe we can
deal with them some other occasion but
so yeah once a person does get attain to
the stream entry through their proper
mindfulness of the body which is the
development of the understanding or the
stream entry they start realizing the
fruit of the stream entry
then it says if the mindfulness of the
body is made much of properly developed
at least the realization of the fruit
and non returning the fruit of our hand
shaped and yeah there it is again
they will talk about understanding it's
a 584 599 it says one thing as in
mindfulness to the body because
developed made much of leads to the
unattained of understanding leads to the
growth of understanding so you fully
attained the understanding of our hand
shape the growth of understanding the
full development understanding through
practicing mindfulness of the body
so again if something is understood then
means you know that you know it so it's
not some experience that happens to you
it's something that you discern on
account of the nature of experience
that's pretty much right in front of you
so if you're properly mindful your own
understanding your own your own insight
into them and freedom from suffering
inside into Four Noble Truths and so on
gets developed and in the previous suit
as we were reading you could also see
that through the practice of mindfulness
to the body you develop right composure
Samadhi you develop proper Samadhi so basically
you develop proper Samadhi so basically
proper Samadhi then means development of
proper understanding so it's not it's
not a surprise that every time they will
finish by by saying that things a
culminating wisdom an insert in
discernment he wouldn't he wasn't saying
that they come in it is some
overwhelmingly blissful pleasurable
experience that you can't even explain a
put in words far from it sure freedom
from suffering is very pleasant
it's a huge relief it's like crossing
the desert and not knowing whether even
a survivor not and then you survive they
feel a tremendous relief but that's a
that's a very different type of pleasure
that is usually being valued and
sought-after in the contemporary
Buddhist meditations so it continues
here saying leads to the full
development understanding leads the
great understanding leads to wide
understanding leads to the extensive
understanding leads to deep
understanding leads to the non-local
understanding leads to the broad
understanding leads to the abundance of
understanding leads to the quick
understanding the fast understanding
speedy understanding the Swift
understanding the sharp understanding to
penetrate it understanding which one
think mindfulness with the body and then
number 600 says because they do not
enjoy the deathless who do not enjoy
mindfulness of the body and by the way
the reason why well one of the many
reasons why the mindfulness of the body
is so wholesome is because if it's done
properly it thoroughly thoroughly
undermines the slightest sense of
conceit that a person might be able to
entertain otherwise because the body is
just a random you could say a random
thing or a random heap of elements
thrown in the world because of which you
know the world as such which means that
that body has a relationship the
external type of relationship with the
world that you can't even conceive
because your secondary to it and because
of that your whole existence your whole
experience mental experience as well not
just bodily is thoroughly undermined by
it and that's the definition of
understanding impermanence but if you're
just trying to like attend to the
aspects of your body well that's all
they're possible because your body is
there in the
place that's why I keep talking about
the peripheral awareness which is the
awareness the background awareness which
is the awareness the mindfulness you
don't want to attend it on your own
terms or observing sensations or feeling
like this or looking at that that's all
possible on the ground of that body
being already there thrown into that
world and you you have no sane in that
if you fully dwell on that as we read in
the previous talk
you're gonna start experiencing proper
use tension anxiety they will then lead
to proper understanding of freedom and
you can develop something only once you
understand what you're supposed to
develop it doesn't happen to you it
doesn't occur it doesn't completely
divine providence it comes through your
own effort of understanding and that's
it and that's why the deathless is
enjoyed by those who enjoy mindfulness
of the body once you fully understand
that inherent independence of a heap of
the elements upon which your whole life
depends well you stop appropriating your
whole life is my life as the life I am
in control of it just remains standing
there like a palm stump you stop you
stop feeding it with with desire and
greed and craving and so on and and
there is the deathless relinquishing it
all or you kind of licorice it all
willingly intentionally because any
intention of apathy Gina is on the basis
of non relinquishment so even if he
tries to relinquish things he's
appropriating that act so you really
want to undermine yourself so to speak
you can't will your way out of
enlightenment but you can certainly set
it up and it will then result in it and
you set it up by seeing that you're your
own will your own life depends upon
things that you cannot will in control
it's inseparable from it's bound with
the definition of Sankara so when you
fully understand those things
discerned them as the fundamental reason
for you being able to let say yes or no
and do other things and choose and so on
that's how you disown even your own
volition so then here the the suitors
continue six six hundred to six and A
three four to saying deathless is missed
by those who mindfulness so the boat is
missed they have neglected the deathless
those who have neglected neglected the
mindfulness of the body the deathless
has been forgotten by those who forgot
mindfulness of the body deathless is not
practiced by those who mindfulness of
the body is not practiced because it
carries on deathless is not developed by
those who mindfulness to the body is not
developed deathless is not discerned by
those mindfulness so the body is not
discerned deathless is not fully
understood by those four who my friend
so the body is not fully understood
deathless is not realized by those who -
the body's not realized now there's a
DXF from singer Tony Kyle
35 and it's a two hundred and forty
seven good time so let's see what it
says suppose we go man with wounds on his
suppose we go man with wounds on his
body with a festering body would go into
a wood of reeds and kusa toe thorns
would pierce his feet the leaves of the
reeds would scratch his limbs that's
because on account of this the man would
experience a huge amount of pain and
unhappiness in just this way because
here a certain Baku who has gone to the
village or gone to the forest meet
someone who says this venerable one is
someone who acts like this who behaves
like this Hilti thorn of the village
having seen thus restraint and non
restraint should be seen in which
because is non restrained
here because a bhikkhu having seen a
sight with the eye inclined
towards a pleasing sight he's troubled
by a displeasing sight and he dwells
without mindfulness of the body set up
with a limited mind limited mind means
mind bound to the foreground mount
control mind controlled by by the object
of their attention
that's what limits it unlimited
boundless is the one who realizes the
the boundless domain of peripheral so
he's troubled by a displeased inside
yeah that's another thing I mean many
people probably think it's it's obvious
and in a way it is obvious but it's one
thing to understand it on the
theoretical level another thing is to
actually start discerning the principle
that you are living then you're acting
out of and then principle is inclining
towards pleasure makes you liable to
pain and that is the inherent danger of
sensuality giving in to sensuality by
sight sound smell taste touches and so
on scent relaxed that is the most direct
reason why you're subject to suffering
that's why the Buddha would say like
even even those who followers of other
are the teachings back in the day would
would sometimes be able to overcome
sensuality and desire to a sensual
pleasures and he would say that they
even they would have abandoned lots of
suffering just by doing that despite all
the wrong views that they would still
have in regard to the other matters
overcoming the first toward sensual
pleasures it's a it's a it's basically
overcoming a huge amount of suffering
and here it's that scene on a very
subtle level obviously so inclining
towards a pleasing sight means you will
be troubled by a displeasing sight it's
the one being matter of choice and until
that's discerned the danger in
sensuality is not apparent as the
suitors would say so you don't the there
is the inherent danger in sensuality
but you have to see it on its own terms
yet to see what it is often people's
contemplation around the sensuality is
like you try to fabricate the danger you
try to tell yourself how it's not worthy
and so on and all that is true but none
of that is direct enough to be seen as a
principle that can actually genuinely
free you from your blind desire towards
it and deadly right principle is seeing
that it's the welcoming of the pleasure
of sensuality that's why you are liable
to pain so that must be seen presently
simultaneously reason that connection
that dependence that determination with
this this is with inclination to it's
pleasure suffering is possible and
possible suffering it's already
unpleasant the fact that suffering might
affect you that is already troubling you
so he says he he he dwells without
mindfulness of the body set up with a
limited mind because he still his mind
is still bound with the objects of his
senses pleasing or displeasing he his
attention controls him and he does not
understand as it really is that
liberation of my liberation of
understanding where those arisen
evil unwholesome things cease for him
without a reminder having heard a sound
with air smells maybe the nose taste the
taste with a tongue touch that touch
with the body
imagine a phenomenon with the mind he
inclines there was a pleasing phenomenon
he's troubled by this pleasing
phenomenon he dwells without mindfulness
with the body set up with a limited mind
suppose because a man having taken hold
of suppose because a man having taken
hold of six animals with different
domains different feeding grounds would
tie them up with a strong rope having
taken hold of a snake he would tie it up
with a strong rope having taken hold of
a crocodile he would tie it up with a
strong rope having taken hold of a bird
he would tie it up with a strong rope
having taken a hold of a dog he would
tie it up with a strong rope I haven't
taken the hold of a jackal he would tie
it up with a strong rope and haven't
taken a hold of a monkey he would tie it
up with a strong rope having tied him up
with a strong rope having made a knot in
the middle he will release them then
because those six animals with different
domains different feeling around with
pull would each pull towards its own
feeding ground and domain the snake
would pull I will enter an anthill
crocodile would say I will enter the
water bird would fly up in the sky dog
would pull thinking I will enter the
village jackal would try to enter the
graveyard and the monkey would pull I
will end in the woods because when these
six animals would be worn out exhausted
then whichever is the strongest out of
the animals they would submit to it they
would follow it they would come under
its control in just this way because for
whatever big mindfulness of the ball is
not developed not made much of I pulled
into the agreeable side disagreeable
sides a repulsive mind poles and so on
for every sensing and he says my
imposing degree of a phenomenon
disagreeable phenomena repulsive this
way because one is unrestrained so so
you could see that even based on this
end previous a ferret
even the practice of restraint is not
like mindless saying no to everything I
mean you might have to start like that
but it shouldn't stay that level they
should certainly not be neurotically
afraid of sight sound smell taste
touches but you want to start discerning
because it says you're properly
restrained when you're mindful of the
body when your mind from the body
the clear understanding is developed
see if there is no clear understanding
of the nature of coucil as Casilla and
our coucil as acasola
there is no mindfulness of the body
present not the proper one at least and
then it says oh yeah continue so and
which because he's restrained here
because a big who having seen a sight
with the eye does not inclined towards
pleasing sight he's not troubled by this
pleasing sight because of that and he
dwells with the mindfulness of the body
set up with an immeasurable mind at
supper man at the poly wood a boundless
immeasurable and he understand as it
release that liberation of mine
liberation of understanding but there's
a reason evil and all something sees
without a remainder
heavenly the son will hear smell no son
son having imagined a phenomenon with
the mind he does not incline toward the
pleasing phenomenon
he's not troubled by this pleasing
phenomenon he dwells with mindfulness
with the body set up with a with an
immeasurable mind he understands as it
really is that liberation of mind
liberation of understanding where those
arisen evil and wholesome things cease
for him without a reminder so again so
he continues with the same simile of
tying down the six different animals
with a strong rope tying the rope in the
middle and then the animals try to pull
towards their respective feeding grounds
but the difference is now with a
properly strained when those six animals
become worn-out exhausted then they just
stand next to it they would just sit
down next day they will lay down next to
the strong steak or post that they've
been pinned down with the rope so just
in this way because for whatever big
kumara so the ball is developed made
much of the eye does not pull into the
agreeable sights disagreeable sad to not
see positive
smell taste touch and so on and then the
mind is not falling to deliver phenomena
so the stronger the stake the post to
which you tie your senses
he's not your determination is not your
point of view it's not your decision to
never engage in these things it's the
presence of the phenomenon of the body
they're peripherally established in that
background is that object in the world
because of which there is the world for
you in the first place the world in this
case being the feeding ground
so you discern that then you don't have
to practice restraint in a sense of you
don't have to be pulling these animals
back because you you have properly tied
them to the post that will make them
tired and then they will have to sit
down so all you have to do is remain
mindful with the body properly and then
your restraint is done for you oh yeah
well there it is so the next paragraph
says the mind does not pull into a grave
a phenomenon disappearo Furman are not
repulsive and this way big who is
restrained and a strong stake of post
this because is a designation for
mindfulness of the body therefore
because you should train in this way
mindfulness of the body will be
developed by us made much of made a
vehicle made a ground
carried out practice properly undertaken
in this way because you should train
so then we have a smoothing got 43 and
but maybe maybe they can be part 3 now
because topic changes he talks about the
undetermined in the path to undetermined
Sun kata okay so we can maybe do that
later